<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?><Search><pages Count="21"><page Index="1" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[LEARNING WITH SODEXO]]></page><page Index="2" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ABOUT YOUR WORKBOOKWelcome to “Learning with Sodexo”, this book includes information on learning styles as well as tools and tips to help you get the best out of your learning and development.This book belongs to you and is aimed at helping you learn more effectively. We hope that you will find it useful and that you enjoy learning with Sodexo.2]]></page><page Index="3" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[CONTENTSIntroductionSupport and commitments Learning stylesActivists Reflectors Theorists PragmatistsSummaryLearning and development in action Managing your timeConcerns & solutionsMaking the most of your development Personal planningContact us]]></page><page Index="4" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[INTRODUCTIONAt Sodexo, we recognise that supporting the learning and development of our people is important and it is one of our strategic priorities. We also recognise that individuals within our organisation can reach their full potential with the right learning and development. We are keen to harness this potential and give employees the opportunity to develop and grow.As an individual, you have your own goals in terms of performance, career aspirations, personal growth and job satisfaction. Effective support will allow you to translate your ambitions into a context that reflects your personal learning needs and enables you to transfer your learning into your workplace.When designing learning and development programmes, we understand that only 10% of anyone’s total knowledge comes from formal, learning, the remainder comes through practical application of knowledge (70%)and working with others who have already developed the sought after abilities (20%).< Contents]]></page><page Index="5" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[We build our programmes and courses to reflect this and offer face to face courses, eLearning, podcasts and many other learning activities. We will also help you to determine how you can implement new knowledge and continue your development practically.Every day is a learning opportunity, and everything we learn will help us deal with new situations more effectively and prepare us for our future. We hope that you enjoy your development and make the most of your learning opportunities.As an equal opportunities employer, Sodexo will work with all team members who advise us of any special requirements they may have for learning support. We want to ensure that everyone has fair access and opportunity to learn and develop; if you have any support requirements that you would like us to help with, please speak to your line manager, your local learning and development contact or the PeopleCentre L&D team.“I’d heard a lot of good things about Sodexo. One of the reasons I wanted to work for a big company was that I felt it would be more suited to my way of thinking. My plan is to havean apprentice or a traineein my team as you cansupport them to developin the company way.”Paul Walker,General Services Manager Sodexo Corporate Services GSK at Slough< Contents]]></page><page Index="6" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ActivistsTheoristsIn order for you to make the most of a learning activity, you must do the following:-• Attend all parts of your programme(s)• Arrive promptly for the scheduled start time of all partsReflectorsof the programme(s)• Dress in business appropriate clothing (unlessspecifically advised of a dress-code)• Be mentally as well as physically present in programmeactivities, giving the learning your full attention andcommitment• Complete all coursework elements on time• Actively take your learning back into the workplace• Continue to develop your skills through activities thatsuit your learning style (working with your line manager)• Engage with your group members to support each otherin developingSUPPORT AND COMMITMENTSYOUR COMMITMENTBy taking part in learning activities, you will gain new knowledge, skills and experiences; however it is up to you to use your abilities within your role. Completing learning activities in isolation will not make any significant change to your role or work.< Contents]]></page><page Index="7" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Your line managerYour facilitatorLearning & Development TeamYour group membersYour line manager will be on hand to help you with your questions, to support you with your pre and post course work and activities. They will also be able to give you learning activities in the workplace that will help you develop your knowledge further.Your facilitator(s) will deliver your courses and will help you learn in an interactive setting using various different learning exercises. They will be available to answer questions and help you if you need further understanding on the topics covered.The Learning and Development Team can advise you and your line manager on any learning activities to help with your development.Everyone taking part in learning programmes have the same challenges, so helping and supportingone another will be beneficial to all of you. Keep in touch with your group members outside of classroom sessions to share your learning, help each other through challenges and share ideas. There are a number of technology platforms available which may help you with this help you with this.YOUR SUPPORTThroughout your learning, a number of people will be able to help and support you make the most of your learning and development, to help you to be successful.< Contents]]></page><page Index="8" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[LEARNING STYLESWhen it comes to learning, we all have a preferred style or way of learning, these styles are characterised as Activist, Theorist, Pragmatist and Reflector. You can find out your personal preference by completing a short questionnaire on this website: www.sodexo.peterhoney.com where you will need to register as a new user with the registration code sdxlnd.The learning styles website will also give you detailed information about each of the preferences, the sorts of activities and experiences that will most likely resonate best with your personal profile and the sort of experiences that you will probably learn least from.To help you understand your preferences and maximise your learning opportunities, here is a summary for each of the styles:ACTIVISTSREFLECTORSTHEORISTSPRAGMATISTS< Contents]]></page><page Index="9" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ActivistsThese are people who involve themselves fully and without reservation in any new learning process. Their philosophy is ‘I’ll try anything new’. They dash in where angels fear to tread! Their days are filled with activity. They thrive on any new challenges.In summary, Activists like:• to think on their feet• to have short sessions• plenty of variety• the opportunity to initiate• to participate and have fun< Contents]]></page><page Index="10" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ReflectorsThese are people who like to stand back to ponder experiences and observe them from many different perspectives. They have to collect data and like to chew it thoroughly before coming to any conclusion. Their philosophy is to be cautious and to leave no stone unturned. They prefer to keep a back seat in meetings and discussions.In summary, Reflectors like:• to think before acting• thorough preparation• to research and evaluate• to make decisions in their own time • to listen and observe< Contents]]></page><page Index="11" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[TheoristsThese are people who adapt observations into logically sound theories. They think problems through in a vertical, step-by-step logical way. They assimilate disparate facts into coherent theories. They tend to be perfectionists, keen on principles, theories, models and systems thinking.In summary, Theorists like:• concepts and models• to see the overall picture• to feel intellectually stretched • structure and clear objectives • logical presentation of ideas< Contents]]></page><page Index="12" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[PragmatistsThese are people who are keen to try out new ideas, theories and techniques. They are usually the first to experiment with applications. They are the sort of people who return from management training courses with new ideas that they want to try out in practice. They do not like beating around the bush and tend to be impatient with open-ended discussions.In summary, Pragmatists like:• to see the relevance of their work• to gain practical advantage from learning • credible role models• proven techniques• activities to be real< Contents]]></page><page Index="13" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[SUMMARYUsing the learning styles, it is possible to assess various learning opportunities and to see which opportunities are most likely to work for you.For example:-Someone needs to learn the features and benefits of a PC for the first time.If the person is:An Activist A ReflectorA TheoristA Pragmatistthey will want to play with the keyboard immediately and see what happensthey will be keen to have a look at the manual quickly, watch someone else working at the PC, think about it, and then come back tomorrow to have another lookthey will want to read the manual before going anywhere near the equipmentthey will want to learn from the experienced person showing them the ropes and have questions answered as they arise.< Contents]]></page><page Index="14" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[LEARNING AND DEVELOPMENT IN ACTIONCASE STUDY 1Before Sodexo, I used to manage a burger van but the owner sold the business. Having done this for 10 years and with the kids now at school, I thought I’d do my part. I applied for a job as a cleaner with Sodexo in October 2006, and a week later started my new role.I started off preparing food, making packed lunches, cleaning hot plates and mopping floors. I wanted to progress so I trained in all the chemicals and after six months I was promoted to supervisor. One day the Head Chef was unwell, so with one of the army chefs as my mentor, I cooked the breakfast. I then decided to start training as a chef. When I started doing an NVQ, funded by Sodexo, they brought in an NVQ Assessor. The course was supposed to be 18 months, but the assessor came in twice a month and we finished in half the time. I qualified as a chef in August 2008. I started asa junior rank chef. Then in 2011, I was moved to the Sergeants’ Mess for training purposes, then to the Officers’ Mess for further training.In February 2014, I completed an IOSH course, a level 3 in Supervising food safety and in August I became Head Chef. Now I manage three food service assistants. I’m happy in my role at the moment. Soon, I would like to be Catering Manager, overseeing all the messes.Marie Ward, Head ChefSodexo DefenceParsons Barracks Donnington, Telford< Contents]]></page><page Index="15" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[CASE STUDY 2I joined Sodexo nearly 9 years ago at 18 years old as an unskilled maintenance assistant with the aim of training in my chosen discipline through college. I studied air conditioning and refrigeration for 3 years and went on to become a mobile engineer, then maintenance supervisor, contract supervisor and now in mobilisations.I always had an inquisitive mind, taking things apart to see how they worked so to move into maintenance and engineering seemed like a good prospect. I knew the Operations Manager at Sodexo from a previous part time job that I held. I researched the company and was impressed with what I saw so I agreed to take up the position. I don’t think I realised at the time that he was giving me an interview!I didn’t have an official mentor when I joined, but I was part of an incredible team. Everyone helped from the Engineering Team leader to the Operations Director and the Administrators. I worked closely with my Team Leader as he was an Air Conditioning Engineer (my chosen discipline) who had a wealth of technical knowledge that he passed on. Hopefully I retained some of it!The main benefits of working for Sodexo in my eyes are the opportunities for progression and the colleagues that I have the pleasure to work with. There are so many dedicated, passionate, caring and helpful people within the business.The thing I have enjoyed most has been meeting new people and building up a network of contacts. I also love the variety of tasks that I get involved in, knowing that there are usually other opportunities just around the corner.I would strongly recommend undertaking an apprenticeship. There is no substitute for experience in the workplace and so many things that can’t be taught in a classroom.Thomas Kebble, Mobilisations Project Manager Technical ServicesSodexo Corporate Services< Contents]]></page><page Index="16" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[MANAGING YOUR TIMEAn important part of your development is making the time to learn and being able to manage your own learning effectively.Planning learning activities will help you to get the best learning experiences and will also give you time to digest what you learn, reflect on it and determine what you need to do next.Important elements for you to plan are listed below:• Sessions• Dates • Times• Locations- How to get there- Where to park, if driving- Any likely traffic/travel delays • Specific dress-codes• Coursework• What needs to be done• When it needs to be done by• What needs to happen when it is done• Extra reading or research• What you are required to read / research• How you can access learning (online / SodexoNet,reading etc)• When you can get access to complete this (i.e. if theoffice computer is required)< Contents]]></page><page Index="17" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[LEARNING CONCERNS & SOLUTIONThink about the amount of time you have available for learning. What concerns do you have that may be obstacles to your learning?Draw out a table like the one opposite, discuss your concerns with your manager and identify some solutions for each.Concern Solution< Contents]]></page><page Index="18" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[MAKING THE MOST OF YOUR DEVELOPMENTPERSONAL DEVELOPMENTWhile learning programmes consist of sessions where the content and coursework has been pre-determined this is not the only learning that you can do. Your learning style preference will help you identify your preferred way of learning and direct you to some activities that will enhance your learning further.In general there are several types of activity that help people to learn, such as:• Experience• Having a go, driving is a good example, as experiencing it is theonly way to learn how to drive• Listening• Picking up knowledge through hearing what people say or discuss• Observation• Watching your manager/colleagues complete various tasks• Talking/discussion• This helps to form opinions< Contents]]></page><page Index="19" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[MAKING THE MOST OF YOUR DEVELOPMENT• Reading• This increases knowledge• Making mistakes• If you dropped something on your foot and it hurt, you would learnthat you should move your foot next time• Routine/repeating things• Do things enough times until they become second nature• Fun/games• Fun activities with a learning outcome (usually on classroomcourses)• Feedback from line managers or learning specialists • Reflection on your actions• What you have done, how it worked and whether the outcome was acceptablePERSONAL DEVELOPMENT CONT...All of these activities can be used with any subject or topic and in a variety of different settings such as on-the-job, in meetings or on training courses.Speak to your line manager and identify three areas / topics / tasks within your working environment that you would like to learn more about. Refer to this list to help you select the best activities that you can use to learn.< Contents]]></page><page Index="20" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[PERSONAL PLANNINGHere is an example of a development plan for you to use, a blank copy can be downloaded from SodexoNet.For Ingenium users, you should make use of the “My Development Plan” tool on Ingenium as this will keep your plans and training record together.Learning ActivityWhat do I want to learn more about?What can I do to learn more about it?Who do I need help fromHow long will it take me?How will I measure my progress?ExampleRunning meetings – how to build an agenda, how to make notes of the meeting and what to do after the meetingAttend meetings in my unitSpend some time with my line manager to look at agendas and notes from old meetingsLine manager3 monthsCreate and send out a full meeting agenda. Attend the meeting and take the notes. After the meeting, type up the notes and send them outWhen you have completed this development plan and all the activities within it, use the same format to create further development plans.< Contents]]></page><page Index="21" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[CONTACT USIf you have any questions about a learning activity or you would like to let us know about anything relating to your learning, please send an email, or ask your manager to send an email to peoplecentre.uk@sodexo.com starting the subject line with “L and D Team” (do not include the quotation marks) and someone will get back to you as soon as they can.If you don’t have access to email or would rather talk to us, you can telephone the PeopleCentre on:0845 603 3644 and choose option 2 for L&D.You can also get in contact with the UK and Ireland L&D team on twitter by following us:@SDX_Learning_UK #SDXLnD]]></page></pages></Search>